Guide to the Joseph B. Keller Papers SC0899
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Joseph B. Keller papers
1949-2007
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Keller, Joseph B. (Joseph Bishop)
SC0899
20.5 Linear Feet 30 boxes
These papers consist primarily of correspondence files maintained by Keller from 1949-2007. Also included are article reviews and refereeing reports, honorary degrees and other awards, and course evaluations, as well as figures and problems.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Joseph B. Keller is Professor Emeritus of Mathematics and of Mechanical Engineering at Stanford University, and former Honorary Professor of Mathematical Sciences at the University of Cambridge. Born in Paterson, New Jersey in 1923, Keller earned all three of his degrees at New York University: B.A. in 1943, M.S. in 1946, and Ph.D. in 1948. He remained there as a Professor of Mathematics in the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences until 1979, when he moved to Stanford University, where he continues to conduct his research.
Description of the Collection
These papers consist primarily of correspondence files maintained by Keller from 1949-2007. Also included are article reviews and refereeing reports, honorary degrees and other awards, and course evaluations, as well as figures and problems.
Mathematics -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Department of Mechanical Engineering; Stanford University. Department of Mathematics; Keller, Joseph B. (Joseph Bishop)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - January 1973-December 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - January 1947-August 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - September 1975-June 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - July 1976-January 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - April 1977-December 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - January 1978-May 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - August 1979-February 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - March 1980-December 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - July 1980-December 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - January 1981-June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - January 1981-June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - July 1981-December 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - January 1, 1982-June 30, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - July 1, 1982-December 31, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - January 1, 1983-April 1, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - April 1, 1983-June 30, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - July 1, 1983-August 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - October 1983-February 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - February 1984-July 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - September 1984-January, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - September 1984-April 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - October 1984-April 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - May 1985-August 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from various files, contracts, etc., circa 1977-1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - October 1985-March 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - September 1986-December 1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - September 1992-December 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1993-1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1988-1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Spring 1997 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1997 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Jesse Goldberg, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1996-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 2000 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 2002 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 2002-2004 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 2000-2004 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 2005-2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Calendars, 1981-1985 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Figures (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Figures: Reflected rays (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes, problems (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Course Evaluations-Stanford & UCLA (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Old Applicants (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Articles reviewed, July 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Articles reviewed, January 1968-September 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Articles reviewed, January 1975-December 1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, January 1980-October 1981 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Reviews, November 1981-1983 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1992-1998 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, 1998-2005 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - United States National Committee on Theoretical and Applied Mechanics (Keller), and Stanford Committee on Research, 1981-1982, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Wave Motion (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Monthly Problems (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1980-2002 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Awards Programs, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Map of Greenwich Village (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Award-New York University Service Citation, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Award-New York University Founders Society, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Honorary Degree-Universidad Carlos III De Madrid, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Degree-The University of Notre Dame (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-100
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-132
  - Biographical, Press Releases (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, Lecture Transp. List (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PhD Students (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publications (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abstracts (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Awards (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Appointment (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Mathematics in the Spirit of Joe Keller" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Slides (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photograph - Colloquium in honor of JBK's 80th (Box 2, Folder 4)